IT'S A CRIME WHAT PRISON CAN DO TO A GIRL!
Scrubbers is a drama film directed by Mai Zetterling.
Inmates fight, pair off, try suicide and attempt escape
at a British reform school for girls.
Carol Howden, played by Amanda York.
Annetta Brady, played by Chrissie Cotterill.
Kathleen, played by Elizabeth Edmonds.
Eddie, played by Kate Ingram.
Mac, played by Amanda Symonds.
Glennis, played by Kathy Burke.
Scrubbers is a 1982 British drama film directed by Mai Zetterling and produced by
Don Boyd starring Amanda York, Kathy Burke, and Chrissie Cotterill.
It was shot primarily in Virginia Water, Surrey, England.
It was inspired by the success of the 1979 film Scum.
A novel based on the film, and also entitled Scrubbers, was
written by Alexis Lykiard and published in London by W.
Allen & Co.
The film explores themes of prison, prisoner, nun, juvenile prison, black humor.
The tone is emotional.